myrelatives.com 2015-04-28

# Privacy

**March 23, 2015**

This Privacy Policy is applicable to all site users, including new and returning visitors. By using this site, you agree to abide by our Terms of Use and the policies stated in this Privacy Policy. MyRelatives (“site”, “us”, “our” or “we”) owns this website and has developed this Privacy Policy to provide details about the collection, use and disclosure of information collected on the site or interactive properties owned by us, including but not limited to mobile applications and mobile websites. By using the site or registering an account, you agree to accept and abide by the terms of this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use. 

MyRelatives has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through.myrelatives.com and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications and mobile websites. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). 

**_PERSONAL INFORMATION YOU SHARE WITH US:_**

MyRelatives may collect information about you to help us provide the most relevant search results possible. We also collect information that you provide to us during the Account Creation process. Please review the following sections to learn more about what type of information we may collect and how that information can be used. 

**Registration and billing information**

When you register on this website, we may collect the following information:

  * Name
  * Email
  * Account Password
  * Debit/Credit Card Number and Security Code
  * Billing Zip 

This information is necessary to create your account and process your membership subscription. It is also used to verify your identity and confirm current, future and ongoing transactions. If you do not create an account, this information is not retained. Billing information is stored securely and only shared with third parties who are involved in verifying and completing transactions. 

**Genealogy searches**

While running genealogy searches, you may enter information about a third party, such as a name, address and birth year. This information is used exclusively to provide you with search results. The length of time this information is retained is at our discretion. It may be stored to help you process future searches. 

**Family trees**

When you register with MyRelatives, you may choose to build a family tree. Please note that the information you include or add to your family tree may either be kept private or shared publicly. If you choose to share your family tree publicly, then other MyRelatives members may access it and use the information therein to help build their own family tree. Please Note: we make no guarantee of the validity or accuracy of information that any user has voluntarily contributed to their family tree. Your family tree may be deleted at any time. We reserve the right to retain information that was included in public family trees, even after they have been deleted. 

**Optional information**

There may be times when you are asked to provide additional information about yourself, feedback to the company or other types of optional information. It is up to you to decide whether or not you choose to disclose this information or provide feedback. We encourage users to provide feedback and other such information, as this helps us to improve our services and offer a better experience for you. If you choose to provide this information, MyRelatives retains the right to use and/or disclose it at our sole discretion. Any such feedback, content or other information is irrevocably assigned to MyRelatives, and we do not have any obligation of confidentiality (express or implied) regarding the feedback you provide. You agree that you are not entitled to any type of reimbursement or compensation under any circumstances if you provide feedback or any other optional information. 

**_INFORMATION COLLECTED VIA TECHNOLOGY:_**

In addition to any information collected through the means described above, MyRelatives and our third party service providers may collect additional information during your visit to this site. This may include the IP address used to access this site and the type of device used to access this site. Such information may be collected to: 

  * Help us remember the searches you conducted so we may offer a better experience upon your return
  * Provide information and suggestions based on your preferences and usage history 
  * Analyze the traffic to this site 
  * Determine which type of devices most commonly access this site 
  * Determine your geographic location 

The information we collect that is not Personally Identifiable Information may be used for any purpose we deem appropriate. We reserve the right to share such non-personal information with third parties. At times, third party service providers may also collect information about you during your visit to MyRelatives.com. We do not have any access to or control over the tracking technologies owned and operated by these service providers. You may choose to disable cookies or take other steps so that these types of information may not be collected, but then certain features of this site may not function properly. 

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by MyRelatives and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and gathering demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference) and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited. 

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash to store information. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 and Flash to collect and store information. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>. 

**_INFORMATION COLLECTED FROM THIRD PARTY SOURCES:_**

At times we may collect information from trusted third party service providers. This is done to supplement the information you provided. For example, it may be used to update your address or billing information or to obtain relevant demographic information. This information is used to help us maintain accurate information, to help us tailor any communications that we send to you, and for internal analysis or other business related purposes. 

**Social Media**

The MyRelatives site may provide links to various social media platforms. If you click these links, then they may collect information such as your IP address and set a cookie that allows them to function properly. Any interaction you have with these social media links/features is governed by the Privacy Policies of the appropriate third party service provider. 

**_HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION:_**

**Use by us**

  * To provide you with information about new and upcoming features, services or products
  * To provide you with information that you requested/agreed to receive 
  * For internal business purposes (analyzing data, enhancing existing products, etc.) 
  * To improve our services 
  * To make suggestions that may enable you to expand your family tree 
  * To customize your experience on this website 
  * To verify your identity
  * To improve our services 
  * For purposes that are disclosed when you provide your personal information 
  * For any other purpose that has been declared within this Privacy Policy 

**Our contact with you**

When you sign up for our services or contact us for any purpose, you may provide contact information including a phone number, email and address. When you do so, you agree that it constitutes either a purchase or an initiation of a business relationship with MyRelatives. You agree that this signifies your consent for us to communicate with you using the contact information you provided. You may be contacted in one or more ways, including but not limited to a telephone call (in person or from a recorded message), email, text (SMS), or any other applicable method of communication. 

**Transactional communication**

When you complete any type of transaction on MyRelatives.com, we may send you a notice or confirmation. Transactional communications may include order confirmations, customer service notifications, invoices or other relevant communications. If it becomes necessary, we may also send service-related communications. An example of a service-related communication would be a notification that an order is temporarily delayed, a service is temporarily unavailable or other relevant scenarios. These communications are not promotional, so you may not opt out of receiving them. 

**Promotional Communications**

From time to time you may receive emails about special offers, discounts, new services or other promotions. You may choose to opt out of receiving these promotional communications and then you will no longer receive them. You may opt out of receiving promotional communications in two ways: 

  1. Every promotional email we send will include an Unsubscribe link at the bottom. When you click this link, we will automatically unsubscribe you from our mailing list. 
  2. When logged in to your account, click the “My Account” link and then update your settings under “Email Preferences.”

Once you have Unsubscribed, we cannot guarantee that you will never receive another promotional email from us. We may obtain your email address again in the future through another marketing program that you subscribe to. If this should happen, you may opt out again using the methods listed above. Please note that even if you opt out from promotional communications, you may still receive transactional communications from us related to your account, orders your place and other services. You may not opt out from these transactional communications. 

**Legal matters**

Under certain circumstances we may, without your permission or consent, disclose your personal information or any communications that we received from you (this includes, without limitation, the contents of any message, chat, email or other communication from you) along with any additional information we have about you or your account as is permitted or required by law (including, but not limited to court order or subpoena). These circumstances include, but are not limited to: 

  * To investigate or prevent potential fraud, violations of our Terms of Use, anything that may expose us to legal liability, or any activity that appears to be illegal.
  * If your conduct while using this site, communicating with, or otherwise engaging with this site is in any way deemed inappropriate and not consistent with generally accepted behavioral norms.
  * In cases of emergencies that may involve potential threats to a person’s safety, the safety of any physical property, or if we believe that the information you provided may in any way relate to such a threat. 

**Sale/Transfer of business and/or assets**

In the event that this site, or any businesses owned by this company, is sold or disposed of as a going concern (this could be by a sale of assets, merger, bankruptcy, insolvency or any other method), then any Personally Identifiable Information that we have obtained from our members and/or visitors to this site may be listed as an asset that will be sold or merged as part of that transaction. Information that we receive from customers and/or registered users may also be disclosed in the event of a commercial transaction in which we, or any other business under our control, are seeking funding, financing, support or investments. If such a transaction occurs, then the Personally Identifiable Information will be subject to the pre-existing Privacy Policy that was in effect when that information was initially acquired. 

**_ACCESSING OR UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION_**

If you believe that the personal or billing information you provided to us is outdated or incorrect, then you may review and update that information after logging in to your account and accessing the “My Account” section. You may also contact our customer service team at http://myrelatives.com/contactus.aspx for assistance. In the event that you change/update your information, we may still retain the information you initially provided for various reasons, including but not limited to: 

  * Recordkeeping integrity 
  * Analytical purposes
  * Enforcing our Terms of Use or other policies 
  * Preventing fraud 
  * Resolving disputes 
  * Taking any and all necessary actions due to technical and legal requirements/constraints related to the security, operation and integrity of this site and all related sites and applications 

Additionally, if third parties have already collected information about you in compliance with the policies described above, then the retention of that information is subject to their policies. 

**_OPTING OUT RECORDS FROM THIS SITE_**

MyRelatives.com gives you the ability to block records from being shown on this site. You can request for your personal information to be blocked from being searched by using our opt out form (see the link below). We only have the ability to block records that are under our control. Opting records out on this site will not opt them out from any other site that is not under our control. We reserve the right to require verification of your validity to opt out certain records, and may reject opt out requests at our sole discretion. To opt records out of this site, please fill out the form here. The changes you request may not be effective immediately, but we will comply with your request as quickly as is reasonably possible. Despite any opt out request we receive and honor, we may need to retain the information for recordkeeping purposes. There may also be information that remains in our database and other records, and that information will not be changed or removed 

**_COMPANY PRACTICES AND DISCLOSURES_**

**Links to other sites**

MyRelatives may contain links to third party sites and communities. Please note that these external, third party sites are not under our control, and are therefore not subject to any part of this Privacy Policy. If you visit these or any other sites, we recommend that you read their Privacy Policies thoroughly. 

**Testimonials**

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us here: http://www.myrelatives.com/contact. 

**Public Directory**

We may list you in a publicly accessible member directory. If you wish to request removal of your information from our directory, you can opt out of our site here. 

**Security**

While we take great lengths to keep your information secure, please note that no data transmission that is conducted online, via wireless transmission or through electronic storage can be guaranteed as 100% secure. Additionally, we cannot ensure that the information you transmit to us will be 100% secure. Your use of this site indicates your understanding and acceptance of this. 

**International Users**

MyRelatives is operated exclusively in the United States. Visitors from outside of the United States should be aware that any information we collect will be transferred to, processed and stored within the United States. The data protection laws we adhere to might be different than the laws in the country from which you access this site. Your Personal Information may be subject to access requests from governments, law enforcement, courts or other United States agencies in accordance with the laws of the United States. By using this site you consent to the application of United States federal and California state laws in all matters concerning MyRelatives.com and this Privacy Policy. 

**Updates to this Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy. When changes are made, we will post the most recent version here, and update the “Last Updated” date seen above. We may choose to revise this Privacy Policy to reflect a change in our practices, technology changes, when we add new or update existing services, or for any other reason we deem necessary at our sole discretion. In the event that we change the way we use or manage any Personal Information, we will give you a reasonable opportunity to consent to that change. Should you choose not to consent, then your Personal Information will be used/managed in accordance with the Privacy Policy that was in effect during the time when we obtained the information. 

**Disputes**

Any visit to this site, or other sites and applications under our control is done at your own discretion. Any dispute you may have is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, including resolution of disputes, limitations on damages and application of the laws of the United States and the State of California. 

**No rights for third parties**

The Privacy Policy creates no rights that are enforceable by third parties or that require disclosure of any Personal Information relating to users of this site. 

**CONTACT US**

If you have questions about our site, services or membership levels, then please send us an email using the form found at http://myrelatives.com/contactus.aspx 

Our business hours are: 

Monday - Friday: 7:00am - 6:00pm PST   
Saturday - Sunday: 7:00am - 11:30am PST   
and 12:30PM - 3:30PM, Closed 11:30AM - 12:30PM   
Thank you for visiting the MyRelatives Privacy Policy. 

Copyright ©2015 MyRelatives.com. All rights reserved.
